### **Eric Simmons**

615-481-3124

Nashville, TN

Ericnrgnash@gmail.com

Github: Github.com/EricEnergy

Linkedin: Linkedin.com/in/ericSimmonsNash

Personal Site: https://ericenergy.github.io/mern-My-Portfolio

#### SUMMARY

Goal-oriented web developer with strong commitment to collaboration and solutions oriented problem-solving. Utilizes various web design software to develop customer-focused websites and designs. Committed to high standards of web design, user experience and usability for multiple types of endusers. Graphic design background results in judicious, creative, effective websites, apps, and platforms, which propel competitive advantage and revenue growth.

# **EDUCATION**

- Vanderbilt University Coding Boot Camp (Full Stack Web Development)
- 5 years Leadership in Sales mentoring program

#### STRENGTHS & PROFESSIONAL SKILL SET

- Ability to work quickly and efficiently with strong eye for detail
- Marketing and sales management
- Proven ability to work well under tight deadlines

- Knowledgeable in Microsoft Office Suite and CRM management tools
- Ability to work within groups and independently

#### CODING, DESIGN AND MISC SKILLS

- HTML, CSS
- Node.is, NPM
- MongoDB
- Photoshop
- Bootstrap/Foundation
- Express
- Jest, Mocha
- Illustrator
- jQuery, AJAX
- MySQL, Sequelize
- Git
- Visual Studio
- JavaScrpit/[ES5,ES6]
- React.js
- Google Suite
- Microsoft Suite

# EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

# **Full Stack Engineer**

DollarMetro / Dec 2019 - Current

- Front-End development Ecommerce React web application
- Restful API design, implementation, and testing
- Backend implementation of NodeJs services
- Development tools (React, Express, JS, NodeJs, MySQL, Material-UI)
- Working with a team on UI and mobile-first design

#### **Quality Control Specialist**

Hudson Yards - LSC Communications / Apr 2018 - Oct 2019

- · Assist in developing and maintaining color corrections, retouching and QC standards for all clients
- Responsible for companywide mark-up of in-house content
- Provide color correction, cut-out, banding solution, extension and background replacement services
- Expertise in concept development and realism

#### **Account Executive**

Chyron Hego/Click Effects | Jan 2017 - Nov 2017

- Creation and standardization of \$30k \$500k quotes
- Generated sales leads for warranty deals valued between \$8k \$100k
- Responsible for audio sales in all territories resulting in 25% annual sales growth
- Develop new sales strategies for Audio Department while identifying new business prospects
  Manage prospective leads and existing accounts through SalesForce CRM platform

Click Effects | Jan 2014 - Jan 2017

**Client Relations Specialist** 

- Creation and standardization of \$30k \$500k quotes
- Read diagrams and RFPs for current projects to delegate client needs
- Generated sales leads through client outreach programs
- Proactive customer support process leading to 98% approval and 84% client return

# **Logistics Coordinator**

Click Effects | Jan 2011 - Jan 2014

- Read diagrams and RFPs for current projects to delegate client needs
- Generated sales leads through client outreach programs
- Serve as the program manager for the implementation of new CRM tool
- Design and implement procedures across workplace to effectively enhance data integrity

# PROJECTS - CODE | SITE

Pet Store Swagger App - https://github.com/EricEnergy/swaggerPetStoreReact/tree/master/src/pages | https://ericenergy.github.io/swaggerPetStoreReact/#/

- This basic React app was created to showcase my current skillset
- This app features React written with a functional and class component
- NOTE Data is open to the public and can be anarchic

# Serv App - https://github.com/EricEnergy/mern-finalproject | https://serv-project.herokuapp.com

- This application is intended as a tool for small business owners in the service industry to connect with customers interested in their skills via a social media app which also utilizes a calendar to make appointments online
- Role included back end heavy 3rd party API integration, building routes, building React forms and front end design
- Tools / languages used: MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Material-UI, and Cloudinary

# Garaged App - <a href="https://github.com/EricEnergy/garaged">https://garaged-app.herokuapp.com</a>

- Garaged was created to be an 'Airbnb-type' app, but for vehicles. Its purpose is for anyone with extra garage space to make a post in their city, that someone with a lack of space can then rent out for a fee
- Role included back end design with setting up Bcrypt and Passport functionality, as well as heavy front-end design
- Tools / languages used: Node Express, Express Handlebars, Sequelize, Passport, BCrypt, CSS, Bootstrap, API Cloudinary, jQuery, Chai, and Jest

# Trip Planner App - https://github.com/EricEnergy/tripAssistant Project | https://ericenergy.github.io/tripAssistant Project

- This app allows users to enter a city they are visiting, and they are then given a list of categories of places they can visit. From the selected list they are then shown a list of available activities or events that can then be saved to their calendar
- Role included back end development, namely creating routes for data management, as well as integrating and testing all code from other project contributors
- Tools / languages used: MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Material-UI, and Cloudinary